Student Clubs and Organizations, A-Z Files, 1880-[ongoing]
Smith College Archives
Student Clubs and Organizations, A-Z Files
1880-[ongoing]
Smith College.
RG 80 UUID:e978590d-58f5-453b-b7f8-1434278cf0f3
27 boxes (11.23 linear ft.)
Smith College Archives Northampton, MA
The Student Clubs and Organizations, A-Z files contains charters, flyers, photographs, programs, articles, and notes documenting most of the student organizations since Smith was founded.
The Student Club Files contain information on most of the organizations since Smith College was founded. The records range from the early 1900s to the mid-2000s. Student clubs were formed as a way for Smith College students to engage with one another outside of the classroom. Activities of the clubs included academic, social, and political work. The clubs listed here are not those clubs associated with a particular academic pursuit. Information about these clubs may be found with the departmental records of the specific department in 52. Departments of the classification system. The types of material vary from club to club, but may include charters, flyers, photographs, programs, articles, and notes. Many folders have very little material in them, which often doesn't yield much information about the specific organizations. Usually, each organization's file contains at least a copy of the charter and a few photographs.
There are several clubs and organizations for which there are a wide variety of materials. Many of these records are separated into individual boxes and some have separate finding aids. If there is a note that an organization has a finding aid or separate box, please consult with a reference archivist.
The files are arranged alphabetically by club or organization name.
The records are open for research according to the regulations of the Smith College Archives without any additional restrictions.
The Student Clubs and Organizations, A-Z files were donated over a period of time to the Smith College Archives from a variety of sources.
- General (Box 3001)
- Active Minds 2007- (Box 3001)
- African Students Association 1988-1993 (Box 3001)
- AIESEC - L'Association Internationale des Etudiants en Sciences Economiques Et Commercials c1960s-1980s (Box 3001)
- Al-Iman 1990-2010 (Box 3001)
- Alpha & Alpha Phi Kappa Psi 1882-1970, See finding aid and separate boxes. (Box 3001)
- American Field Service undated (Box 3001)
- American Student Union 1936-1945 (Box 3001)
- American Youth for Democracy 1945-1949 (Box 3001)
- Amnesty International 1993 (Box 3001)
- Ancient Order of Hibernians 1890-1950, See finding aid and separate boxes. (Box 3001.1)
- Animal Advocates of Smith College (AASC) (Box 3001.1)
- Art Resources Committee 1986-1993, undated (Box 3001.1)
- Artis Amor 1979-1980 (Box 3001.1)
- Arts Guild 1947-1949 (Box 3001.1)
- Asexual Communication and Education Club (ACE) (Box 3001.1)
- Association of Asian Students 1986-1995 (Box 3001.1)
- Association of Low-Income Students 1992-1995 (Box 3002)
- Association of Smith Pagans 1994-1995 (Box 3002)
- Bad Seeds 1994-1995, undated (Box 3002.1)
- Best Buddies 2008 (Box 3002.1)
- Bicycle Kitchen 2008- (Box 3002.1)
- Black Students Alliance 1969-, See finding aid and separate boxes. (Box 3002.1)
- Blue Pencil Club 1917-1929 (Box 3002.1)
- B'nai B'rith Hillel Foundations, See Religious Organizations finding aid and separate boxes. (Box 3002.1)
- Camera Club 1938-1953 (Box 3003)
- Celebrations Dance Company 1996-2002 (Box 3003)
- Ceramics Club 1982, undated (Box 3003)
- Chapel Players 1993-1994, undated (Box 3003)
- Chinese Inter Regional Student Cultural Organization (CISCO) (Box 3003)
- Clamshell Alliance 1979 (Box 3003)
- Clef Club, See Music Department--Clubs finding aid (Box 3003)
- College Bowl Team 1960-1966 (Box 3003)
- College Campus United Nations 1950-1953 (Box 3003)
- College Model Security Council 1976 (Box 3003)
- College Relief Committee 1957 (Box 3003)
- Committee for Peace 1987-1990 (Box 3003)
- Celebration 1991-, See finding aid and separate box. (Box 3003.1)
- Community Garden 2009-2010 (Box 3004)
- Concerned Students of All Colors 1987-1988 (Box 3004)
- Consumer's League 1912-1937 (Box 3004)
- Cooperative Discount Association 1900 (Box 3004)
- Cosmopolitan Club 1929-1940 (Box 3004)
- Current Affairs Council 1954 (Box 3004)
- Current Events Club 1905-1953 (Box 3004)
- Dance Club 1923 (Box 3004)
- Debate Club 1900-, See finding aid and separate boxes. (Box 3004)
- Delta Society 1895-1897 (Box 3004)
- Democratic Club 1932-1995 (Box 3004)
- Departmental Clubs--General 1922-1942, See also separate departments. (Box 3004)
- EKTA - South Asian Students of Smith 1987- (Box 3004.1)
- Eleven Votes for Peace 1968 (Box 3004.1)
- Elf Club 1896 (Box 3004.1)
- Emergency Medical Technicians 1997 (Box 3004.1)
- Engineers for Sustainable World (ESW) (Box 3004.1)
- Environmental Club 1979-1980 (Box 3004.1)
- Ethical Investment Committee 1987 (Box 3004.1)
- Feminists of Smith Unite (FSU) 1997-1998 (Box 3004.1)
- Film Alliance 1984-1990 (Box 3004.1)
- Five College Christian Science Organization 1995 (Box 3004.1)
- Flying Club 1932-1945, See finding aid and separate boxes. (Box 3004.1)
- Foreign Students and Student Lecture Committee undated (Box 3004.1)
- Garrett Club undated (Box 3004.1)
- Gold Key Organization 1946-1996 (Box 3004.1)
- Granddaughters' Society 1904-1966, See finding aid and separate boxes. (Box 3004.1)
- Green Age Literary Collective 1985-1988, undated (Box 3004.1)
- Heather's Curling Club 1953 (Box 3004.1)
- Indigenous Americans of Smith 1995 (Box 3004.2)
- International Affairs Organization 1958- (Box 3004.2)
  - Foreign Students 1929-1966, See separate boxes. (Box 3004.2)
- International Association of Students In Business and Economics (IASEB) undated (Box 3004.2)
- International Development Forum 1987-1988 (Box 3004.2)
- International Relations Club 1923-1965, See separate boxes. (Box 3004.2)
- International Student Service 1929-1946, See separate boxes. (Box 3004.2)
- International Students Organization 1945-1995 (Box 3004.2)
- Investment Club (Box 3004.2)
- Judo Club 1983-1988 (Box 3004.2)
- Kappa Kappa Gamma 1934-1951 (Box 3004.2)
- Korean American Students at Smith 1985-1995 (Box 3004.2)
- Ku Klux Klan 1907 (Box 3004.2)
- Labor Relations Group 1932-1945 (Box 3004.2)
- Lesbian, Bisexual, and Transgender Alliance c1970-, See finding aid and separate boxes. (Box 3004.2)
- Liberal Association 1952-1953 (Box 3004.2)
- Logics Club 1940 (Box 3004.2)
- Luba Club, see: Hampshire House (Box 3004.2)
- Manuscript Club 1910-1912, undated (Box 3004.2)
- Marxist Study Group 1937-1948 (Box 3004.2)
- MASSPIRG 1978-1994 (Box 3004.2)
- Minority Association of Pre-Med Students 2009 (Box 3004.2)
- Multiethnic Interracial Smith College (MISC) 2012- (Box 3004.2)
- Muslim Democrats 2009- (Box 3004.2)
- NAACP 1954, 1987-1988 (Box 3004.2)
- National Affairs Club undated (Box 3004.2)
- National Coalition Building Institute 1994 (Box 3004.2)
- National Student Association, See finding aid and separate boxes. (Box 3004.2)
- Newman Club, See Religious Organizations finding aid and separate boxes. (Box 3004.2)
- Nosotras 1983- (Box 3004.3)
- Novel Club undated (Box 3004.4)
- Odd Volumes Club 1936-1938 (Box 3004.4)
- Old Letters Club 1925-1934, See finding aid and separate boxes. (Box 3004.4)
- Omega Society c1910 (Box 3004.4)
- Onlooker's Club c1920 (Box 3004.4)
- Orangemen c1908-1936, 1986 (Box 3004.4)
- Oriental Club c1902-1935 (Box 3004.4)
- Outing Club 1990, undated, See also Athletics finding aid. (Box 3004.4)
- Pan-American Club 1950-1952 (Box 3004.4)
- Peer Sex Education 2001-2008 (Box 3004.4)
- People for Choice 1990-1991 (Box 3004.4)
- People's Lobby, See Student Demonstrations finding aid and boxes (Box 3004.4)
- Phi Beta Kappa 1972 (Box 3004.4)
- Philosophical Society 1895 (Box 3004.5)
- Phoenix Club 1938-1939 (Box 3004.4)
- Photography Club 1988- (Box 3004.4)
- Pleiades 1912-1921 (Box 3004.4)
- Poetry Club 1935 (Box 3004.4)
- Political Association and Clubs 1939-1965 (Box 3004.4)
- Polity Club 1917 (Box 3004.4)
- Pottery Club 1982 (Box 3004.4)
- Presidential Elections c1880s-1968, 1980 (Box 3004.4)
- Pre-Theological Society 1979 (Box 3004.4)
- Prism 2012- (Box 3004.4)
- Progressive Club 1938-1952 (Box 3004.4)
- Pro-Life Alliance 1994-1998, See finding aid and separate boxes. (Box 3004.4)
- Public Affairs Club 1952 (Box 3004.4)
- Pug Wash 1994-1996 (Box 3004.4)
- Pulse 1996 (Box 3004.4)
- Queer Action Coalition undated (Box 3004.4)
- Quidditch undated (Box 3004.4)
- Radio Club and Student Radio Stations 1947-, See finding aid and separate boxes. (Box 3004.4)
- Rape Awareness Workshop c1990 (Box 3004.4)
- Reading Clubs 1880-1889 (Box 3004.5)
- Republican Club 1929- (Box 3004.5)
- Resource Center for Sexuality & Gender 2008- (Box 3004.5)
- Rugby-Football Club, See Athletics finding aid. (Box 3004.6)
- Sazanami (Box 3004.6)
- Secret Societies 1951 (Box 3004.6)
- Smith African and Caribbean Students Association 2007- (Box 3004.6)
- Smith Association of Class Activists 2007- 2011 (Box 3004.6)
- Smith Breast Health Collective 2007-2009 (Box 3004.6)
- Smith Coalition Vote 2000 (Box 3004.6)
- Smith Committee on Central America 1987 (Box 3004.6)
- Smith Experimental College 1971-1974 (Box 3004.6)
- Smith Improv and Komedy Organization of Smith 1994 (Box 3004.6)
- Smith in India 1953 (Box 3004.6)
- Smith Middle East Committee 1991 (Box 3004.6)
- Smith Peace Committee c1948 (Box 3004.6)
- Smith Project on Sexual Harassment 1985-1989 (Box 3004.6)
- Smith Science Fiction and Fantasy Club, See separate boxes. (Box 3004.6)
- Smith Spirit Cheerleading (Box 3004.6)
- Smith To Do (Box 3004.6)
- Smith Tsunami Relief Committee 2005 (Box 3004.6)
- Socialist Club 1932-1994 (Box 3004.7)
- Society for a Complete Curriculum 1987-1988 (Box 3004.7)
- Society of Women Engineers 1986-1995 (Box 3004.7)
- Society Organized Against Racism 1985-1992 (Box 3004.7)
- Solidarity 1995 (Box 3004.7)
- South African Students Association 1994 (Box 3004.7)
- Speakers' Forum 1935 (Box 3004.7)
- Spectator Society 1912 (Box 3004.7)
- Speech Club 1995 (Box 3004.7)
- SpitFire Smith College (Box 3004.7)
- Students Against Sexual Assault 2010- (Box 3004.7)
- Student Bank, See Treasurer - Student Bank. (Box 3004.7)
- Student Book Exchange 1947 (Box 3004.7)
- Student Escort Service 1993-1994 (Box 3004.7)
- Student Events Committee (SEC) 1993-1994 (Box 3004.7)
- Student Film Alliance (Box 3004.7)
- Student Grassroots Organizing Group 2001-2002, See separate boxes. (Box 3004.7)
- Student Labor Action Coalition 2000-2002 (Box 3004.7)
- Student Theatre Committee 1995 (Box 3004.7)
- Student Theater Organization 1993 (Box 3004.7)
- Students for a Peaceful Response 2001-2007 (Box 3004.7)
- Students for Camp Heartland 2009 (Box 3004.7)
- Students for Justice in Palestine (SJP) (Box 3004.7)
- Students for Social Justice and Institutional Change 2003-, See separate boxes. (Box 3004.8)
- Students Together Against Abusive Relationships 1991 (Box 3004.8)
- Studio Club 1948-1949 (Box 3004.8)
- Survivors and Advocates for Education on Incest And Childhood Sexual Abuse (SAFE) 1996 (Box 3004.8)
- Tae Kwon Do 2009 (Box 3004.8)
- Thistle Club 1930s (Box 3004.8)
- Thistle Club-Tartan and Cap undated (Box 3004.8)
- Transcending Gender 2011- (Box 3004.8)
- Union of Under-Represented Science Students undated (Box 3004.8)
- United Nations, See College Campus UN (Box 3004.8)
- United Student Employee Delegation 1991-1992 (Box 3004.8)
- United World Federalists 1946-1952 (Box 3004.8)
- Unity News, See 34. Dean of the College: Assistant Dean for Minority Affairs (Box 3004.8)
- Victory Club undated (Box 3004.8)
- Voice for Choice (VOX) 2007- (Box 3004.8)
- Why Club 1929-1982 (Box 3004.8)
- Woman Suffrage Club 1913-1921 (Box 3004.9)
- Women Discovering Business 2000-2001 (Box 3004.9)
- Women's Liberation Movement 1971 (Box 3004.9)
- Women's Multicultural Network 1985 (Box 3004.9)
- Women's Resource Center, See finding aid and separate boxes. (Box 3004.9)
- Workout Club 1983 (Box 3004.9)
- Workshop for Jewish Awareness 1992-1993 (Box 3004.9)
- World Affairs Committee 1987-1995 (Box 3004.9)
- Young Americans for Freedom 1965-1966 (Box 3004.9)
- Young Democrats Club 1963-1964 (Box 3004.9)
- Alpha Society 1896-1952, undated (Box 3005)
- Alpha Society 1878-1940, undated (Box 3006)
- Alpha Society 1878-1916 (Box 3007)
- Alpha Society 1879-1968 (Box 3008)
- Alpha Phi Kappa Psi 1879-1968 (Box 3008)
- Arts Festival 1957-1970, undated (Box 3009)
- Phi Kappa Psi 1892-1939, undated (Box 3010)
- Phi Kappa Psi 1892-1934 (Box 3011)
- Ancient Order of the Hiberians (A.O.H.) 1894-1966, undated (Box 3011.1)
- Debate Society 1900-1980, undated (Box 3012)
- Flying Club 1934-1950, undated (Box 3013)
- Granddaughters' Society 1904-1966, undated (Box 3014)
- Foreign Students 1929-1966, undated (Box 3015)
- International Relations Club 1933-1964, undated (Box 3015)
- International Affairs Organization 1929-1980, undated (Box 3015)
- International Student Service 1940, undated (Box 3015)
- Lesbian Bisexual Transgender Alliance 1971-2003, undated (Box 3016-3016.1)
- National Student Association 1947-1965, undated (Box 3017)
- Old Letters Club 1776-1876, undated (Box 3017.1)
- Pro-Life Alliance 1989-1997, undated (Box 3017.2-3017.4)
- Republican Club 2005- (Box 3017.5)
- Science Fiction and Fantasy Club 1980-1994, undated (Box 3018)
- No Box (Box 3019)
- Sophomore Push 1961-1987, undated (Box 3020)
- Student Grassroots Organizing Group (SGOG) 2001-2004 (Box 3020.1)
- Students for Social Justice and Institutional Change 2003- (Box 3020.2)
- Women's Resource Center 1974-1990, undated (Box 3021)